Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
[TIRES SCREECH]
GRUMPY: Three of a kind, let's do this.
CHUCKLES: That's it? Three guys?
GRUMPY: Two guys on the roof. Every
guy gets a share. Five shares is plenty.
CHUCKLES: Six shares. Don't
forget the guy who planned the job.
GRUMPY: He thinks he can sit it out
and still take a slice.
- I know why they call him the Joker.
HAPPY: Why do they call him the Joker?
DOPEY: I heard he wears makeup.
HAPPY: Makeup?
DOPEY: Yeah, to scare people.
You know, war paint.
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
GRUMPY: All right, everybody,
hands up, heads down!
I said, hands up, heads down!
Let's go, pal,
I'm making a withdrawal here.
- I said, hands up!
- No!
DOPEY:
Here comes the silent alarm.
And there it goes.
GRUMPY:
Heads down!
All right, tootsie,
you're taking a dive with me.
- Down! I said, stay down there!
WOMAN: Don't hurt me!
DOPEY: Funny, it didn't dial 911.
It was trying to reach a private number.
HAPPY: Is it a problem?
DOPEY: No, I'm done here.
[SILENCED GUNSHOT]
GRUMPY:
Sit down! Down!
Down! I said, stay down there!
GRUMPY: Obviously we don't want you
doing anything with your hands...
...other than holding on for dear life.
CHUCKLES:
On the ground! Stay on the ground!
Nobody make a move!
Nobody! Stay down!
[SHOTGUN BLAST]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]
Yeah!
You have any idea
who you're stealing from?
- You and your friends are dead.
GRUMPY: He's out, right?
[SHOTGUN BLAST]
GRUMPY:
What...?
Where did you learn to count?
HAPPY: They wired this thing up
with like 5000 volts.
What kind of bank does that?
GRUMPY: A Mob bank.
I guess the Joker's as crazy as they say.
Where's the alarm guy?
HAPPY: Boss told me when the guy
was done, I should take him out.
One less share, right?
GRUMPY:
Funny, he told me something similar.
HAPPY:
He what? No! No!
GRUMPY:
That's a lot of money.
If this Joker guy was so smart,
he'd have had us bring a bigger car.
[GUN COCKS]
I'm betting the Joker told you to kill me
soon as we loaded the cash.
BOZO:
No, no, no, I kill the bus driver.
GRUMPY:
Bus driver?
What bus driver?
DRIVER:
School's out. Time to go.
That guy's not getting up, is he?
That's a lot of money.
What happened to the rest of the guys?
MANAGER:
You think you're smart, huh?
The guy that hired youse...
...he'll just do the same to you.
Oh, criminals in this town
used to believe in things.
Honor...
...respect.
Look at you.
What do you believe in, huh?
What do you believe in?!
I believe whatever doesn't kill you
simply makes you...
...stranger.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[MOANS]
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
MAN 1: Mr. Mayor, you were elected
in a campaign to clean up the city.
- When are you gonna start?
MAN 2: I already have.
MAN 1: Like this Batman.
We're hearing he's doing good,
criminals are running scared.
- No, man. I don't like it tonight.
- What are you, superstitious?
You got more chance of winning
the Powerball than running into him.
That's not true. Our men in the
Major Crimes Unit are close to an arrest.
Hey, Wuertz, mayor says
you're closing in on the Batman.
The investigation is ongoing.
MAYOR: The process of cleaning up
the streets is a long one.
I pledged in my campaign, uh, to have...
Ever intending to see your wife again,
lieutenant?
I thought you had to
go look after your mother, detective.
Checked her back into the hospital.
I'm sorry.
- So he hasn't shown up?
- He often doesn't.
I like reminding everybody
he's out there.
Why wouldn't he come?
Hopefully...
...because he's busy.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
That's why we bring dogs.
- My little princes.
MAN: Please.
Please, they're crawling in my mouth.
Please, I beg you, get them off.
CHECHEN: Look what your drugs
do to my customers.
SCARECROW:
Buyer beware.
I told you my compound
would take you places.
I never said they'd be places
you wanted to go.
My business, repeat customers.
SCARECROW: You don't like
what I have to offer...
...you can buy from someone else.
Assuming Batman left anyone
to buy from.
[BARKING]
My dogs are hungry.
Pity there's only one of you.
[THUG 1 YELLS]
[THUG 2 YELLS]
[GUN COCKS]
CHECHEN: What...?
SCARECROW: That's not him.
Loose the dogs!
[SCREAMS]
SCARECROW:
That's more like it.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GRUNTING]
[YELLING]
[DOG GROWLS]
[YELLS]
[DOG WHIMPERS]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Don't let me find you out here again.
- We're trying to help you.
BATMAN: I don't need help.
Not my diagnosis.
What gives you the right? What's
the difference between you and me?
I'm not wearing hockey pads.
OFFICER:
Everybody back now!
[REPORTERS CLAMORING]
He can't resist showing us his face.
GORDON:
What's he hiding under that makeup?
RAMIREZ: Uh, can we get a minute,
people, please?
Him again. Who are the others?
Another bunch of smalltimers.
[DEVICE CLICKING]
BATMAN:
Some of the marked bills I gave you.
My detectives have been
making drug buys with them.
This bank was another drop for the Mob.
That makes five.
- We found the bulk of their dirty cash.
- Time to move in.
We'd have to hit all banks
simultaneously. SWAT teams, backup.
What about this Joker guy?
One man or the entire Mob? He can wait.
When the new DA hears about this,
he'll want in.
- Do you trust him?
- Be hard to keep him out.
I hear he's as stubborn as you are.
ALFRED:
Be nice when Wayne Manor's rebuilt.
You can swap
not sleeping in a penthouse...
...for not sleeping in a mansion.
Whenever you stitch yourself up,
you do make a bloody mess.
Yeah. It makes me learn
from my mistakes.
You ought to be pretty knowledgeable
by now, then.
My armor.
I'm carrying too much weight.
I need to be... I need to be faster.
I'm sure Mr. Fox can oblige.
- Did you get mauled by a tiger?
- It was a dog.
- Huh?
- It was a big dog.
There were more copycats last night,
Alfred, with guns.
Why not hire them,
take the weekend off?
That wasn't exactly
what I had in mind...
...when I said I wanted
to inspire people.
I know.
But things have improved.
Look at the new district attorney.
BRUCE:
I am, closely.
Need to know if he can be trusted.
Are you interested in his character
or his social circle?
Who Rachel spends her time with
is her business.
I trust you don't have me followed
on my day off.
If you ever took one, I might.
Know your limits, Master Wayne.
Batman has no limits.
- Well, you do, sir.
- Well, can't afford to know them.
And what's gonna happen
on the day that you find out?
We all know how much you like to say
"I told you so."
On that day, Master Wayne,
even I won't want to.
Probably.
[DOOR OPENS]
MAN:
Sorry I'm late, folks.
[DOOR CLOSES]
- Where were you?
- Worried you'd have to step up?
- Harvey, I know these briefs backwards.
- Well, then...
...fair's fair.
Heads, I'll take it. Tails, he's all yours.
Yeah? You wanna
flip a coin to see who leads?
My father's lucky coin. As I recall,
it got me my first date with you.
I wouldn't leave something like that
up to chance.
I don't. I make my own luck.
BAILIFF: All rise.
The Honorable Judge Freel presiding.
I thought the DA just
played golf with the mayor.
Teeoff's 1:30. More than enough time
to put you away for life, Sally.
With Carmine Falcone in Arkham...
...someone must have stepped up
to run the so-called family.
Is that man in this courtroom today?
- Could you identify him for us, please?
- You win, counselor.
It was me.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
I have a sworn statement from you
that this man...
...Salvatore Maroni, is the new head
of the Falcone crime family.
Maroni? He's a fall guy.
I'm the brains of the organization.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
JUDGE: Order.
- Permission to treat...
...the witness as hostile?
- Granted.
- Hostile? I'll show you hostile!
[CROWD GASPS]
[GUN CLICKS]
Carbon fiber, .28 caliber,
made in China.
If you wanna kill a
public servant, Mr. Maroni...
...I recommend you buy American.
JUDGE: Get him out of here.
- But, Your Honor, I'm not done.
[CROWD CHUCKLING
AND APPLAUDING]
We'll never be able to link the gun
to Maroni, so we can't charge him.
But they're trying to kill you,
means we're getting to them.
I'm glad you're so pleased, Rachel.
I'm fine, by the way.
Come on, Harvey. You're Gotham's DA.
You're not getting shot at,
you're not doing your job right.
But, you know...
...if you said you were rattled,
we could take the rest of the day off.
Can't. I dragged the head of
the Major Crimes Unit down here.
Oh, Jim Gordon? He's a friend, actually.
Try to be nice.
I hear you got a hell of a right cross.
It's a shame Sal's going to walk.
Yeah, well, good thing about the Mob
is they keep giving you second chances.
Lightly irradiated bills.
Fancy stuff for a city cop. Have help?
We liaise with various agencies...
Save it, Gordon. I wanna meet him.
Official policy is to arrest the vigilante
known as Batman on sight.
Mm-hm. What about that floodlight
on the top of MCU?
If you got problems
with malfunctioning equipment...
...I suggest you take them up
with Maintenance, counselor.
I've put every money launderer
in Gotham behind bars...
...but the Mob
is still getting its money out.
I think you and your friend
have found the last game in town.
You're trying to hit them
where it hurts, their wallets.
It's bold.
You gonna count me in?
In this town, the fewer people know
something, the safer the operation.
I don't like that you got
your own special unit...
...and it's full of cops
I investigated at Internal Affairs.
If I didn't work with cops
you'd investigated while at IA...
...I'd be working alone.
I don't get political points
for being an idealist.
I do the best I can with what I have.
You want me to back warrants
for search and seizure on five banks...
...without telling me what we're after.
I can give you the names of the banks.
Well, that's a start.
I'll get you your warrants,
but I want your trust.
Oh, you don't have
to sell me, Dent.
We all know you're Gotham's
white knight.
Yeah, well, I heard they have
a different name for me down at MCU.
I wouldn't know about that.
MAN: In China, Lau Security Investments
stands for dynamic new growth.
A joint Chinese venture with
Wayne Enterprises will be a powerhouse.
FOX:
Well, Mr. Lau...
...I speak for the rest of the board...
...and Mr. Wayne,
in expressing our own excitement.
Sir, I know Mr. Wayne is curious about
how his trust fund gets replenished...
...but, frankly, this is embarrassing.
You worry about the diligence,
Mr. Reese.
I'll worry about Bruce Wayne.
It's done.
The numbers are solid.
Do them again.
Wouldn't want the trust fund to run out,
now, would we?
[SCOFFS]
FOX:
Another long night?
This joint venture was your idea,
and the consultants love it.
But I'm not convinced.
Lau's company has grown by
8 percent annually like clockwork.
His revenue stream
must be off the books...
...maybe even illegal.
Okay. Cancel the deal.
You already knew.
Just needed a closer look at their books.
Anything else you can trouble me for?
I need a new suit.
Yeah. Three buttons
is a little '90s, Mr. Wayne.
I'm not talking fashion, Mr. Fox,
so much as function.
You wanna be able to turn your head.
Sure make backing out
of the driveway easier.
I'll see what I can do.
Took three weeks
to get a reservation here.
I had to tell them
I work for the government.
- Really?
- Health inspector's...
...not afraid to pull strings.
Rachel. Fancy that.
Yeah, Bruce. Fancy that.
Rachel, Natascha. Natascha, Rachel.
- Natascha. Are you the prima...?
- Prima ballerina for the Moscow Ballet.
- Wow. Harvey's taking me next week.
- Really? So you're into ballet?
Bruce. This is Harvey Dent.
The famous Bruce Wayne.
Rachel's told me everything about you.
I certainly hope not.
- Let's put a couple tables together.
- I'm not sure that they'll let us.
Oh, they should. I own the place.
How could you want to raise children
in a city like this?
Well, I was raised here.
I turned out okay.
Is Wayne Manor in the city limits?
Is...? Heh-heh.
The Palisades? Sure.
You know, as our new DA,
you might wanna figure out...
...where your jurisdiction ends.
I'm talking about the kind of city
that idolizes a masked vigilante.
Gotham City is proud of an ordinary
citizen standing up for what's right.
Gotham needs heroes like you,
elected officials...
...not a man who thinks
he's above the law.
Who appointed the Batman?
We did. All of us who stood by
and let scum take control of our city.
NATASCHA:
But this is a democracy, Harvey.
DENT:
When their enemies were at the gates...
...the Romans would suspend democracy
and appoint one man to protect the city.
It wasn't considered an honor,
it was a public service.
Harvey, the last man
that they appointed...
...to protect the republic
was named Caesar...
...and he never gave up his power.
- Okay, fine.
You either die a hero...
...or you live long enough
to see yourself become the villain.
Whoever the Batman is, he doesn't
wanna do this for the rest of his life.
How could he? Batman is looking for
someone to take up his mantle.
NATASCHA:
Someone like you, Mr. Dent?
Maybe. If I'm up to it.
What if Harvey Dent
is the Caped Crusader? Hm?
If I were sneaking out every night,
someone would've noticed by now.
Well, I'm sold, Dent,
and I'm gonna throw you a fundraiser.
That's nice, but I'm not
up for reelection for three years.
No, you don't understand.
One fundraiser with my pals...
...you'll never need another cent.
[METAL DETECTORS
BEEPING AND WHINING]
What the hell is this?
As you're all aware,
one of our deposits was stolen.
A relatively small amount, 68 million.
Who's stupid enough to steal from us?
Two-bit wackjob,
wears a cheap purple suit and makeup.
He's not the problem. He's a nobody.
The problem is our money
being tracked by the cops.
Thanks to Mr. Maroni's
well-placed sources...
... we know that police have indeed
identified our banks using marked bills...
... and are planning to
seize your funds today.
And since the enthusiastic new D A has
put all my competitors out of business...
...I'm your only option.
MARONl: So, what are you proposing?
LAU: Moving all deposits to
one secure location, not a bank.
- Where, then?
- No one can know but me.
If the police were to gain leverage
over one of you...
... everyone's money would be at stake.
What stop them getting to you?
I go to Hong Kong,
far from Dent's jurisdiction...
... and the Chinese will not extradite
one of their own.
MARONl:
How soon can you move the money?
LAU:
I already have.
For obvious reasons, I couldn't wait
for your permission.
Rest assured, your money is safe.
[JOKER LAUGHING]
Oh, hee-hee, aha.
Ha, ooh, hee, ha-ha, ha-ha.
And I thought my jokes were bad.
Give me one reason why I shouldn't
have my boy pull your head off.
How about a magic trick?
I'm gonna make this pencil disappear.
Ta-da!
It's...
It's gone.
Oh, and by the way,
the suit, it wasn't cheap.
- You ought to know, you bought it.
CHECHEN: Sit.
I want to hear proposition.
JOKER:
Let's wind the clocks back a year.
These cops and lawyers
wouldn't dare cross any of you.
I mean, what happened?
Did your balls drop off? Hm?
You see, a guy like me...
- A freak.
MOBSTER 1: Damn right.
A guy like me... Look, listen.
I know why you choose
to have your little, ahem...
...group-therapy sessions
in broad daylight.
I know why you're afraid
to go out at night.
The Batman.
See, Batman has shown Gotham
your true colors, unfortunately.
Dent, he's just the beginning.
And as for the television's
so-called plan...
...Batman has no jurisdiction.
He'll find him and make him squeal.
I know the squealers when I see them...
...and...
CHECHEN:
What do you propose?
It's simple. We, uh, kill the Batman.
[MOBSTERS CHUCKLING]
If it's so simple, why haven't
you done it already?
If you're good at something,
never do it for free.
How much you want?
Uh, half.
[MOBSTERS LAUGHING]
GAMBOL: You're crazy.
- No, I'm not.
No, I'm not.
If we don't deal with this now...
...soon...
...little Gambol here won't be able
to get a nickel for his grandma.
Enough from the clown!
Ah, ta-ta-ta. Let's not blow...
MOBSTER 2: Shit!
...this out of proportion.
You think you can steal from us
and just walk away?
- Yeah.
GAMBOL: I'm putting the word out.
Five hundred grand for this clown dead.
A million alive, so I can teach him
some manners first.
All right. So, listen,
why don't you give me a call...
...when you wanna start taking things
a little more seriously?
Here's my card.
Mm-mm.
You're a hard man to reach.
Lau's halfway to Hong Kong.
If you'd have asked,
I could have taken his passport.
All that was left in the vaults
were marked bills.
They knew we were coming.
As soon as your office got involved...
My office?
You're sitting down there with scum like
Wuertz and Ramirez and you're talking...
Oh, yeah. I almost had your rookie
cold on a racketeering beat.
Don't try and cloud the fact that clearly
Maroni's got people in your office, Dent.
We need Lau back...
...but the Chinese won't extradite
a national under any circumstances.
If I get him to you,
can you get him to talk?
I'll get him to sing.
We're going after the Mob's life savings.
Things will get ugly.
I knew the risk when I took this job,
lieutenant.
How will you get him back, any...?
He does that.
Our Chinese friends left town
before I could tell them the deal was off.
Well, I'm sure that you've always
wanted to go to Hong Kong.
What's wrong with a phone call?
I think Mr. Lau deserves
a more personal touch.
FOX: Now, for high-altitude jumps...
...you're going to need oxygen
and stabilizers.
Well, I must say,
compared to your usual requests...
...jumping out of an airplane
is pretty straightforward.
BRUCE:
What about getting back into the plane?
- I'd recommend a good travel agent.
- Without it landing.
Now, that's more like it, Mr. Wayne.
The CIA had a program
back in the '60s...
...for getting their people out
of hot spots called Sky Hook.
- We could look into that.
- Yeah.
Okay. Now...
Hardened Kevlar plates
over titanium-dipped...
...tri-weave fibers for flexibility.
You'll be lighter, faster, more agile.
Perhaps you should
read the instructions first?
- Yeah.
- Now, there is a tradeoff.
Separation of the plates makes you
more vulnerable to knives and gunfire.
We wouldn't wanna make things
too easy, now, would we?
How will it hold up against dogs?
We talking rottweilers or Chihuahuas?
Should do fine against cats.
I found one in Arizona.
A very nice man said he could have it
up and running in a week...
...and he takes cash.
- What about the flight crew?
- South Korean smugglers.
They run flights into Pyongyang,
below radar.
- Did you think of an alibi?
- Oh, yes.
I believe this is your plane, sir.
You look tired, Alfred.
You'll be all right without me?
If you can tell me the Russian for
"apply your own bloody suntan lotion."
Yo, Gambol, somebody here for you.
They say they've just killed the Joker.
BOD YGUARD:
They brought the body.
So, dead, that's 500.
How about alive? Hm?
You wanna know how I got these scars?
My father was...
...a drinker...
...and a fiend.
And one night,
he goes off crazier than usual.
Mommy gets the kitchen knife
to defend herself.
He doesn't like that...
...not one bit.
So, me watching...
...he takes the knife to her,
laughing while he does it.
He turns to me and he says:
"Why so serious?"
He comes at me with the knife.
He sticks the blade in my mouth.
"Let's put a smile on that face."
And...
Why so serious?
Now...
...our operation is small...
...but there is a lot of potential...
...for aggressive expansion.
So which of you fine gentlemen
would like to join our team?
Oh. There's only one spot open
right now, so we're gonna have...
...tryouts.
Make it fast.
MAN:
Welcome to Hong Kong, Mr. Fox.
Mr. Lau regrets he is unable
to greet you in person today.
FOX:
I understand.
For security purposes, I'm gonna have to
ask you to check in your mobile.
Of course.
I must apologize for leaving Gotham
in the middle of our negotiations.
This misunderstanding
with the Gotham police force...
...I couldn't let it threaten my company.
- Of course.
A businessman of your stature
will understand and...
...with you here now, we can continue.
Well, I do appreciate you bringing me
out here in such style, Mr. Lau, but I re...
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
We do not allow cell phones in here.
I'm sorry. Forgot I had it.
No, I really came to tell you that
our business deal has to be put on hold.
You see, we can't afford
to be seen to do business with...
...whatever it is you're accused of being.
I'm sure a businessman of your stature
will understand.
I think, Mr. Fox, a simple phone call
might have sufficed.
Mr. Wayne didn't want you to think
he was deliberately wasting your time.
Just accidentally wasting it.
That's very good, Mr. Lau.
"Accidentally." Very good.
Hey, sir.
There's a better view
from the peak tram.
How's the view from LSI Holdings?
Restricted.
Lau is holed up in there good and tight.
- What's this?
- I had R & D work it up.
Sends out a high-frequency pulse...
...records the response time
for mapping an environment.
Sonar. Just like a...
Submarine, Mr. Wayne.
Like a submarine.
- And the other device?
- It's in place.
Mr. Wayne?
Good luck.
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[BEEPING]
[IN CHINESE]
[GRUNTING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[CHATTERING IN CHINESE]
[LAU SHOUTING IN CHINESE]
[ENGINES RUMBLING]
RACHEL: Look, give us the money
and we'll talk about making a deal.
The money is the only reason
I'm still alive.
Oh, you mean, when they find out that
you've helped us, they're gonna kill you?
- Are you threatening my client?
- No.
I'm just assuming your client's
cooperation with this investigation.
As will everyone.
No? Okay.
Enjoy your time in County, Mr. Lau.
LAU:
Wait!
I won't give you the money...
...but I will give you my clients,
all of them.
You were a glorified accountant.
What could you possibly have
on all of them that we could charge?
I'm good with calculation.
I handled all their investments.
One big pot.
Got it.
One minute.
RICO. If they pooled their money...
...we can charge them
as one criminal conspiracy.
Charge them with what?
In a RICO case, if you can charge
one of them with a felony...
You can charge all of them with it.
That's great.
Mr. Lau.
What kind of details do you have
about this communal fund?
- Ledgers...?
- Immunity, protection...
...a chartered plane back to Hong Kong.
- After you testify in open court.
I'm just curious.
With all your clients locked up...
...what's gonna happen
with all that money?
Like I said, I'm good with calculation.
He can't go to County.
I'll keep him here in the holding cells.
What is this, Gordon, your fortress?
Well, you trust them over at County?
I don't trust them here.
Lau stays.
Well, I don 't know about
Mr. Lau's travel arrangements...
... but I'm sure glad he's back.
Put word out. We hire the clown.
He was right.
We have to fix real problem.
Batman.
- I'm not aware of any participation...
- Our boy looks good on the tube.
You sure you wanna embarrass me
in front of my friends?
Oh, don't worry. They're coming too.
STEPHENS:
Have a nice trip. See you next fall.
WOMAN: Seven hundred
twelve counts of extortion.
Eight hundred and forty-nine
counts of racketeering.
Two hundred and forty-six
counts of fraud.
Eighty-seven counts
of conspiracy murder.
Five hundred and twenty-seven
counts of obstruction of justice.
How do the defendants plead?
[CLAMORING]
Order in the court.
MAYOR: Five hundred and forty-nine
criminals at once.
How did you convince Surrillo
to hear this farce?
She shares my enthusiasm for justice.
After all, she is a judge.
Even if you blow enough smoke
to get convictions out of Surrillo...
...you're gonna set
a new record at appeals.
It won't matter.
The head guys make bail, sure.
But the midlevel guys, they can't.
They can't afford to be off the streets.
They'll cut deals that
include some jail time.
Think of all you could do
with 18 months of clean streets.
LOEB: Mr. Mayor, you can't...
- No, get out. Both of you.
Sit down.
The public likes you. That's the
only reason that this might fly.
But that means it's on you.
They're all gonna come after you now,
and not just the Mob.
Politicians, journalists, cops.
Anyone whose wallet's
about to get lighter.
Are you up to it? You'd better be.
Because they get anything on you...
...and those criminals are back on the
streets, followed swiftly by you and me.
Jesus!
[SIRENS WAILING]
ALFRED: I think your fundraiser
will be a great success, sir.
BRUCE: And why do you think I wanna
hold a party for Harvey Dent?
I assumed it was your usual reason
for socializing beyond myself...
...and the scum of Gotham's underbelly:
To try to impress Miss Dawes.
Very droll, but very wrong.
Actually, it's Dent.
ENGEL [ON TV]: Police released video
footage found concealed on the body.
Sensitive viewers, be aware.
The image is disturbing.
JOKER:
Tell them your name.
Brian Douglas.
[JOKER LAUGHS]
JOKER:
And are you the real Batman?
BRIAN: No.
JOKER: No?
- No.
- No?
Then why do you dress up like him?
[JOKER LAUGHS]
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
BRIAN: Because he's a symbol that we
don 't have to be afraid of scum like you.
Yeah. You do, Brian. You really do.
Huh? Yeah. Oh, shh, shh, shh.
So you think Batman 's
made Gotham a better place? Hm?
Look at me.
Look at me!
You see, this is how crazy
Batman 's made Gotham.
You want order in Gotham...
... Batman must take off his mask
and turn himself in.
Oh, and every day he doesn 't,
people will die.
Starting tonight.
I'm a man of my word.
[LAUGHING]
[BRIAN SCREAMING]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Harvey Dent,
scourge of the underworld...
...scared stiff by the trust-fund brigade.
- I'll be back.
- Rachel.
A little liquid courage, Mr. Dent?
- Thank you. Alfred, right?
- That's right, sir.
Rachel talks about you all the time.
You've known her her whole life.
Not yet, sir.
Any psychotic ex-boyfriends
I should be aware of?
Oh, you have no idea.
[HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
BRUCE: I'm sorry that I'm late.
I'm glad to see
that you all got started without me.
Now, where is Harvey? Where...?
Harvey Dent, the man of the hour.
Where's Rachel Dawes?
She is my oldest friend. Come here.
When Rachel first told me she
was dating Harvey Dent...
...I had one thing to say:
"The guy from those God-awful
campaign commercials?"
"I believe in Harvey Dent."
Yeah, nice slogan, Harvey.
But it caught Rachel's attention.
And then I started to pay attention
to Harvey...
...and all that he's been doing
as our new DA.
And you know what?
I believe in Harvey Dent.
I believe that on his watch,
Gotham can feel...
...a little safer, a little more optimistic.
Look at this face. This is the face
of Gotham's bright future.
To Harvey Dent. Let's hear it for him.
MAN:
Harvey.
Harvey may not know you
well enough...
...to understand you're
making fun of him...
...but I do.
- No, I meant every word.
You know that day
that you once told me about...
...when Gotham would no longer
need Batman?
- It's coming.
- Bruce.
- You can't ask me to wait for that.
- It's happening now. Harvey is that hero.
He locked up half of the city's criminals,
and he did it without wearing a mask.
Gotham needs a hero with a face.
DENT: You can throw a party, Wayne,
I'll give you that.
Thanks again.
You mind if I borrow Rachel?
Lieutenant, that joker card
pinned to the body?
Forensics found three sets of DNA.
- Any matches?
- All three.
The DNA belongs to Judge Surrillo,
Harvey Dent and Commissioner Loeb.
The Joker's telling us
who he's targeting.
Get a unit over to Surrillo's house.
Tell Wuertz to find Dent.
Protective custody.
Where's the commissioner?
- City hall.
- Seal the building.
- No one in or out till I get there.
- Got it.
Gordon. What are you up to?
We're secure. I want a floor-by-floor
search of the entire building.
We believe the Joker's
made a threat against your life.
These are dangerous people.
You're not giving me
a lot of information.
Even we don't know
where you're going.
Take the envelope, get in, open it.
It'll tell you where you're headed.
You can't leave me alone
with these people.
The whole Mob's after you
and you're worried about these guys?
Compared to this,
the Mob doesn't scare me.
Gordon, you're unlikely to discover this
for yourself, so...
...take my word, the police commissioner
earns a lot of threats.
I found the appropriate response
to these situations a long time ago.
Them gunning for you
makes you see things clearly.
Yeah, I bet.
Yeah. It makes you think about things
you couldn't stand losing...
...about who you wanna
spend your life with.
- That's a pretty big commitment.
- Not if the Mob has their way.
You get to explain to my wife...
...why I'm late for dinner.
Sir, the joker card
had traces of your DNA on it.
- Don't do that.
- All right.
- Let's be serious, then.
- Okay.
What's your answer?
I don't have an answer.
How'd they get my DNA?
Somebody with access
to your office or house...
...must have lifted a tissue
or a glass... Wait! Wait!
- Well, I guess no answer is a no.
- Harvey.
- It's someone else, isn't it?
Just tell me it's not Wayne.
The guy's a complete f...
What are you doing?
GORDON:
Oh, shit.
[LOEB COUGHING]
GORDON:
Get a medic!
They've come for him.
We made it.
Stay hidden.
[SHOTGUN BLAST]
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
We are tonight's entertainment.
I only have one question:
Where is Harvey Dent?
You know where Harvey is?
You know who he is?
THUG:
Hands up, pretty boy.
[THUG GRUNTING]
Do you know where I can find Harvey?
I need to talk to him.
Just something little, huh? No.
What's going on out there? Wayne!
Oh, thank God, you've
got a panic room.
MAN: Hey, wait...
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
You know, I'll settle for his loved ones.
We're not intimidated by thugs.
You know...
...you remind me of my father.
I hated my father.
RACHEL:
Okay, stop.
Well, hello, beautiful.
You must be Harvey's squeeze. Hm?
And you are beautiful.
You look nervous. Is it the scars?
You wanna know how I got them?
Come here. Hey.
Look at me.
So I had a wife.
She was beautiful, like you...
...who tells me I worry too much...
...who tells me I ought to smile more...
...who gambles and gets in deep
with the sharks. Hey.
One day they carve her face.
And we have no money for surgeries.
She can't take it.
I just wanna see her smile again. Hm?
I just want her to know
that I don't care about the scars.
So...
...I stick a razor in my mouth
and do this...
...to myself.
And you know what?
She can't stand the sight of me.
She leaves.
Now I see the funny side.
Now I'm always smiling.
[LAUGHS]
You got a little fight in you. I like that.
BATMAN:
Then you're gonna love me.
[GRUNTING]
[BATMAN YELLS]
Drop the gun.
Oh, sure. You just take off
your little mask...
...and show us all who
you really are. Hm?
Let her go.
Very poor choice of words.
[LAUGHS]
[RACHEL SCREAMING]
Are you all right?
Let's not do that again.
- Is Harvey okay?
- He's safe.
Thank you.
Jim, it's over.
As long as they don't get to Lau,
we've cut off their funds.
The prosecution's over.
Nobody's standing up
in front of a judge...
...while judges and police commissioners
are getting blown away.
- What about Dent?
- He's got any sense...
...Dent's halfway to Mex...
DENT:
So where do you keep your trash?
You're due in court. I need you alive
long enough to get you on the record.
You can't protect me.
You can't even protect yourselves.
You refuse to cooperate, you're not
coming back here, you go to County.
How long do you calculate
you'll last in there?
Targeting me won't get their money.
I knew the Mob wouldn't go
down easily...
...but this is different.
They crossed a line.
You crossed the line first.
You squeezed them, you hammered them
to the point of desperation.
And in their desperation, they turned to
a man they didn't fully understand.
Criminals aren't complicated, Alfred.
We just need to figure out
what he's after.
ALFRED:
With respect, Master Wayne...
...perhaps this is a man
you don't fully understand either.
A long time ago, I was in Burma...
...and my friends and I were working
for the local government.
They were trying to buy
the loyalty of tribal leaders...
...by bribing them with
precious stones...
...but their caravans were being raided
in a forest north of Rangoon by a bandit.
So we went looking for the stones.
But in six months, we never
met anyone who traded with him.
One day, I saw a child
playing with a ruby...
...the size of a tangerine.
The bandit had been
throwing them away.
- So why steal them?
- Because he thought it was good sport.
Because some men aren't looking
for anything logical, like money.
They can't be bought, bullied,
reasoned or negotiated with.
Some men just wanna
watch the world burn.
[VOICES SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
WOMAN:
Your name, sir?
JOKER: Eighth and Orchard.
You'll find Harvey Dent there.
BATMAN:
Check the names.
"Richard Dent."
"Patrick Harvey."
Harvey Dent.
I need 10 minutes with the scene
before your men contaminate it.
It's because of you
these guys are dead...
Detective!
Give us a minute, guys.
That's brick underneath.
Gonna take ballistics
off a shattered bullet?
No.
Fingerprints.
Whatever you're gonna do, do it fast.
Because we found his next target.
He's put it in tomorrow's paper.
I'm not sure
you made it loud enough, sir.
What can I do for you, Mr. Reese?
You wanted me to do the diligence
on the LSI Holdings deal again.
Well, I found some irregularities.
Their CEO is in police custody.
No, not with their numbers, with yours.
Applied Sciences. Whole division
of Wayne Enterprises...
...just disappeared overnight.
I went down to the archives
and I started pulling some old files.
Don't tell me you didn't
recognize your baby...
...pancaking cop cars
on the evening news.
Now you got the entire R & D
Department burning through cash...
...claiming it's related to
cell phones for the Army?
What are you building for him now,
a rocket ship?
I want...
...$ 10 million a year
for the rest of my life.
Let me get this straight.
You think that your client...
One of the wealthiest,
most powerful men in the world...
...is secretly a vigilante...
...who spends his nights beating
criminals to a pulp with his bare hands...
...and your plan
is to blackmail this person?
Good luck.
When...
Keep that.
FOX:
This is your original scan.
Here it is reengineered.
And there's the thumbprint he left
when he pushed the round in the clip.
I'll get you a copy.
Mr. Wayne, did you reassign R & D?
Yeah. Government
telecommunications project.
Wasn't aware
we had any government contracts.
You know, Lucius, I'm playing this one
pretty close to the chest.
Fair enough.
ENGEL: With no word
from the Batman...
...even as they mourn
Commissioner Loeb...
...these cops have to wonder if
the Joker will make good on his threat...
...in the obituary column of
The Gotham Times to kill the mayor.
I've checked all the databases.
There are four possibles.
Cross-reference the addresses.
Look for Parkside,
overlooking the parade.
I got one.
Melvin White,
1502 Randolph Apartments.
Aggravated assault,
moved to Arkham twice.
What do you got on the roof?
We're tight, but frankly,
there's a lot of windows up here.
Commissioner Loeb dedicated his life
to law enforcement...
...and to the protection
of his community.
I remember when I first took office...
...and I asked if he wanted
to stay on as commissioner.
And he said he would, provided
I kept my politics out of his office.
Clearly he was not a man who minced
words, nor should he have been.
A number of policies that he enacted
as commissioner were unpopular.
Policies that flooded my office
with angry calls and letters...
- Who's that?
- What happened?
They took our guns.
And our uniforms.
[TICKING]
MAYOR: And as we recognize
the sacrifice of this man...
...we must remember that vigilance
is the price of safety.
Stand by. Honor guard.
Attention. Port arms.
Ready! Aim! Fire!
Ready! Aim!
[TIMER DINGS]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
[GUNSHOTS]
OFFICER:
Stay down! Don't move!
STEPHENS:
Mr. Mayor. Get him out of here.
- I'll see you later.
- Why are you going back?
[GUNSHOTS]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
Get out of here.
Tell me what you know about the Joker.
[CHUCKLING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
No.
I'm sorry, Barbara.
Jimmy, go play with your sister.
Go ahead, honey.
STEPHENS: If there's anything
we can do, anything you need...
...we're here for you.
[BARBARA SOBBING]
Shh.
BARBARA:
Are you out there?
Are you? You brought this
craziness on us. You did!
You brought this on us!
Switch it off, he ain't coming.
He doesn't wanna talk to us.
God help whoever
he does wanna talk to.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
Can't we go someplace quieter?
We can't hear each other talk.
What makes you think
I wanna hear you talk?
What?
[GRUNTING]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
- Yeah?
MAN: Second.
Okay.
- Harvey, where are you?
DENT: Where are you?
I'm where you should be,
at Major Crimes.
I'm trying to deal with all of this mess.
- Can I get the fingerprint analysis?
- Rachel, listen. You're not safe there.
- This is Gordon's unit.
- Gordon 's gone.
RACHEL: He vouched for these men.
- And he's gone.
The Joker's named you next.
God, is there someone, is there anyone
in this town we can trust?
Bruce.
We can trust Bruce Wayne.
No. Rachel, I know
you're his friend, but...
Harvey, trust me.
Bruce's penthouse is now
the safest place in the city.
Then you go straight there.
Don 't tell anybody
and I'll find you there.
I love you.
I want the Joker.
From one professional to another...
...you're trying to scare somebody,
pick a better spot.
From this height,
the fall wouldn't kill me.
- I'm counting on it.
- Huh!
[SCREAMS]
[BONE CRACKS]
[MARONI YELLS]
[MARONI WHEEZING]
- Where is he?
- I don't know where he is. He found us.
He must have friends.
Friends? Have you met this guy?
Someone knows where he is.
Nobody's gonna tell you nothing.
They're wise to your act.
You got rules.
The Joker, he's got no rules.
Nobody's gonna cross him for you.
If you want this guy, you got one way.
But you already know what that is.
Just take off that mask,
let him come find you.
[GROWLS]
Or you can let a couple more people
get killed while you make up your mind.
You wanna play games?
[GUNSHOT]
How's that feel?
- You wouldn't.
- I wouldn't!
- You don't think I will?
- Mm-mm.
No. No, I wouldn't.
That's why I'm not
gonna leave it up to me.
Heads, you get to keep your head.
Tails...
...not so lucky.
So you wanna tell me about the Joker?
[THUG CHUCKLES]
- Let's go again.
- I don't know anything! God, don't!
You're not playing the odds, friend.
Let's do it again.
You'd leave a man's life to chance?
- Not exactly.
- His name's Schiff, Thomas.
He's a paranoid schizophrenic,
former patient at Arkham.
The kind of mind the Joker attracts.
What do you expect to learn from him?
The Joker killed Gordon.
He's gonna kill Rachel.
You're the symbol of hope
I could never be.
Your stand against organized crime...
...is the first legitimate ray of light
in Gotham in decades.
If anyone saw this,
everything would be undone.
The criminals you arrested
would be released...
...and Jim Gordon
will have died for nothing.
You're gonna hold
a press conference tomorrow.
- Why?
- No one else will die because of me.
Gotham's in your hands now.
You can't.
You can't give in.
You can't give in!
Harvey called.
He said Batman's gonna turn himself in.
I have no choice.
You honestly think that's gonna
keep the Joker from killing people?
Maybe not. But I have enough blood
on my hands.
And I've seen now what I would
have to become to stop men like him.
You once told me that
if the day came when I was finished...
...that we'd be together.
Bruce, don't make me
your one hope for a normal life.
Did you mean it?
Yes.
Bruce.
If you turn yourself in,
they're not gonna let us be together.
ALFRED: Logs as well?
BRUCE: Everything.
Anything that could lead back
to Lucius or Rachel.
People are dying, Alfred.
What would you have me do?
Endure, Master Wayne. Take it.
They'll hate you for it,
but that's the point of Batman.
He can be the outcast. He can make
the choice that no one else can make.
The right choice.
No, today I found out
what Batman can't do.
He can't endure this.
Today you get to say "I told you so."
Today, I don't want to.
But I did bloody tell you.
[BRUCE CHUCKLES]
ALFRED: I suppose they're gonna
lock me up as well...
...as your accomplice.
BRUCE: Accomplice? I'm gonna tell them
the whole thing was your idea.
Ladies and gentlemen, I've called
this press conference for two reasons.
Firstly, to assure the citizens
of Gotham...
...that everything that can be done
over the Joker killings is being done.
[CHATTERING]
Secondly, because the Batman
has offered to turn himself in.
But let's consider the situation.
Should we give in
to this terrorist's demands?
Do we really think he's gonna...?
You'd rather protect an outlaw vigilante
than the lives of citizens?
The Batman is an outlaw.
That's not why we demand
he turn himself in...
...we're doing it because we're scared.
We've been happy to let Batman
clean up our streets till now.
MAN 1: Things are worse than ever!
MAN 2: Amen.
Yes, they are.
But the night is darkest
just before the dawn.
And I promise you...
...the dawn is coming.
One day, the Batman will have to answer
for the laws he's broken. But to us...
...not to this madman.
- No more dead cops!
OFFICERS: Yeah!
He should turn himself in!
MAN 3: Give us the Batman! Come on!
MAN 4: Where is he?
So be it. Take the Batman into custody.
WOMAN: What?
MAN 5: Is he here?
I am the Batman.
MAN 6: What?
MAN 7: Come on.
RACHEL:
Alfred.
Why is he letting Harvey do this?
- He went down to the press conference.
- I know. He just stood by.
Perhaps both Bruce and Mr. Dent...
...believe that Batman stands for
something more important...
...than the whims of a terrorist,
Miss Dawes...
...even if everyone hates him for it.
That's the sacrifice he's making.
He's not being a hero.
He's being something more.
Yeah, you're absolutely right.
Letting Harvey take the fall for this
is not heroic at all.
You know him better than anyone.
I do.
Will you give this to him for me?
When the time is right?
How will I know?
It's not sealed.
Goodbye, Alfred.
Bye, Rachel.
[CELL DOOR OPENS]
I didn't have time to talk this through.
What are you doing?
They're transferring me
to Central Holding.
This is the Joker's chance, and when he
attacks, the Batman will take him down.
Listen. This is too dangerous.
We get this guy to County, he's their
problem. The streets will be cleared...
...so let's go.
The convoys stop for no reason.
I hope you got some moves, pal.
He's using you as bait. He doesn't
know if he can get the Joker.
He's failed so far.
How do you know
what he's thinking?
I just do. Anyway,
this isn't just about you.
What about the people
depending on you...
...to clean the city up
and do it honorably and...?
Harvey. Tell everyone the truth.
Heads, I go through with it.
This is your life. You can't leave...
...something like that to chance.
- I'm not.
[ENGINE STARTS]
You make your own luck.
[TRUCK HORN BLARING]
Hey, you wait like everybody else, pal.
What the hell is that?
Obstruction ahead, obstruction ahead!
Damn it! All units divert down
onto Lower Fifth. I repeat, exit down.
Exit down!
Lower Fifth? We'll be
like turkeys on Thanksgiving.
Jesus. Come on, get us out of here.
Let's go.
Listen, we need backup.
We've got company.
We got trouble, guys.
Lock and load!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[CAR HORNS HONKING]
The hell was that?
- These are built for that, right?
- He'll need something...
...a lot bigger to get through this.
What is that?
What is that, a bazooka?
I didn't sign up for this!
Look out.
Look out!
JOKER:
Hmm.
Come on, let's go!
[CONSOLE BEEPING]
[EXPLOSION]
Harvey, Harvey, Harvey Dent.
Oh, excuse me. I wanna drive.
COMPUTER: Scanning all systems.
Scanning all systems.
[JOKER HUMMING]
We gotta get topside.
We need air support, now!
I like this job. I like it.
COMPUTER: Damage catastrophic.
Eject sequence initiated.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org